aua.com 2014-12-17

# Privacy Policy

##  Protecting your data takes top priority with us 

**Protecting your data is important to us** Booking a ticket online? Applying for a job with us? Ordering our newsletter or checking in for your next flight online? 

You are entrusting us with lots of personal data – which we will treat with the utmost of care, as the protection of privacy while handling personal data is our foremost concern in all our business processes. 

By using our website you consent to given privacy policy. 

Given privacy policy applies to this website only. The pages of this website may contain links to other providers within or without Austrian Airlines AG, to whom given Privacy Policy does not apply, and for which we consequently cannot assume liability. 

For the technical and organizational implementation of given website we also make use of selected service providers, who are contractually obliged to process all data received only in accordance with our instructions. 

**Online booking and web check-in  
**  
All personal data collected during visits on our websites will be processed in accordance with Austrian legislation valid at the time (Data Protection Act). All personal data will be encrypted before being transmitted into our booking or check-in system. If you are inactive on our website for longer than 20 minutes (online booking) or 30 minutes (web check-in), we will automatically log you out for reasons of security. 

If you frequently book online, you can save your data in a profile – that way you do not need to re-enter it each time you visit. You can delete those data at any time. We will treat your details as strictly confidential and will not pass them on to third parties for commercial purposes. 

**Collecting and processing personal data  
**  
We save your personal data if you choose to share them with us for instance when registering, participating in a survey, entering a competition or placing a contract (e.g. flight trip). 

Beyond that we analyze the visits on our website with the aim to better understand our customers’ needs and, based on those findings, continuously improve the online platform. To this end we save the IP addresses of our visitors’ Internet service providers by default. The IP address is not linked to an individual person. Within this web analysis we evaluate anonymous, aggregated data for statistical purposes only. 

We use cookies to follow up on our visitors’ preferences and to optimize the appearance of our websites. 

**Disclosure of personal data to third parties  
**  
Your personal data will only be disclosed to third parties if necessary for the completion of a contract or if you have consented to it beforehand. A consent once given can be revoked at any time. 

**Links to other websites** Our website may contain links to other websites. Please note that we cannot exert any influence on other websites and therefore cannot be held responsible for the protection and confidentiality of the data you share when visiting such websites. 

**Data transmission to foreign authorities  
**  
The collection and transmission of personal data to government authorities and national agencies will only be done under legal provisions applicable at the time. 

Please note that all data you provide during a booking may be subject to transmission. For more details, complaints or data information please feel free to contact us on telephone number +43(0)517661000 (at local rates within Austria, Mon-Sun, public holidays 8:00 AM – 8:00 PM) or via our contact forms.  

APIS data (Advance Passenger Information System):   
In many countries aviation companies are legally or officially obliged to transmit passenger data before the arrival of the aircraft in the country of destination, if your destination airport or a connecting airport is situated in such country. Those legal provisions as a rule include the transmission of data of identification and travelling documents (passport, visa) of all passengers aboard. As we normally do not have those data, they need to be collected until shortly before departure. This is more and more done by means of the „machine-readable section“ of modern travelling documents. The collection of data exclusively serves the purpose of direct transmission to the authorities of the country of destination. 

Secure Flight:   
In accordance with the regulations of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) you are obliged to state your full name, date of birth and sex for the purpose of Watch List Screening under 49 U.S.C. section 114 of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 and 49. C.F.R. parts 1540 and 1560. If available, you may also enter your redress number. In case you do not state your full name, date of birth and sex, you may be denied transportation or the right to enter the boarding area. Within its publicized documentation system the TSA may exchange the data you provided with correctional facilities, intelligence services and other organizations. For more on TSA privacy policies, or to review the system of records notice and the privacy impact assessment, please see the TSA Web site at [www.tsa.gov](http://www.tsa.gov/).

Entering a contact person:   
In accordance with the Regulation (EU) No 996/2010 (Regulation No 996/2010 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 20 October 2010 on the investigation and prevention of accidents and incidents in civil aviation and repealing Directive 94/56/EC) we offer you the possibility to enter a contact person’s name, phone number or email address on our homepage, to be contacted in case of an aircraft accident. Those data will be solely used for such purpose and be deleted after the last flight you took. Please note that those data are not linked to your booking and will have to be re-entered in case of a change of booking. 

**Newsletter  
**  
We save your name and email address in order to send you regular information – if requested. You can unregister from our newsletter with every new edition. You will not receive any further items as of then. We will not share your personal data with third parties. 

**Austrian Career Cockpit** Via the Austrian Career Cockpit you can send us your online application directly or request interesting job offers to be sent to you by email. For this service you will need to create a profile containing your personal data. We will treat your details in strict confidentiality and will not pass them on to third parties. You can delete your profile or your online application at any time. To do so, please send an email to [karriere@austrian.com](mailto:karriere@austrian.com).  

 **Data security  
**  
We take technical and organizational safety measures to protect the data you put at our disposal against incidental or wilful manipulation, loss, deletion or unauthorized access. Our safety measures are continuously being improved following new technological developments. Data processing and transmission are done using SSL protocol (Secure Socket Layer). 

Your personal data are being stored at the servers of [book.austrian.com](http://www.austrian.com/) in Germany (Frankfurt). 

**Social plug-ins** Facebook:  
This website contains programmes (plug-ins) of the networking service Facebook. They are being operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. On our website those plug-ins can be identified by the Facebook logo (white “F” on blue background) or the addition “Like” (“Thumbs up”-sign on blue background). When visiting our web pages that contain such a plug-in, your browser directly connects with the servers of Facebook, thereby transmitting the content of the plug-in to your browser, which finally integrates it into the given web page. This process will pass on the information to Facebook that you have visited our website. If, during your visit of our website, you have also been logged in to Facebook via your personal account, then Facebook can link the website visit with this account. By interacting with the plug-in, for instance when clicking the “Like”-button or posting a comment, the information is transmitted directly to Facebook and stored there. If you wish to prevent such data transmission, you have to log out of your Facebook account before visiting our website. Please see Facebook’s Privacy Policy (http://www.facebook.com/policy.php) for further information on the purpose and extent of the data collection, their further processing and use by Facebook as well as your relevant rights and setting options for privacy protection. 

Twitter:  
This website contains programmes (plug-ins) of the social networking platform twitter.com. They are being operated by Twitter, Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. On our website those plug-ins can be identified by the Twitter logo (blue bird). When visiting our web pages that contain such a plug-in, your browser directly connects with the servers of Twitter, thereby transmitting the content of the plug-in to your browser, which finally integrates it into the given web page. 

This process will pass on the information to Twitter that you have visited our website. If, during your visit of our website, you have also been logged in to Twitter via your personal account, then Twitter can link the website visit with this account. By interacting with the plug-in, for instance when clicking the Tweet-button, the information is transmitted via your browser directly to Twitter and stored there. If you wish to prevent such data transmission, you have to log out of your Twitter account before visiting our website. Please see Twitter’s Privacy Policy (<http://twitter.com/privacy>) for further information on the purpose and extent of the data collection and their further processing and use by Twitter as well as your privacy protection. 

**Cookies  
**  
A so-called „browser cookie“ is a very small text file which a web server (e.g. the web server of [www.austrian.com](http://www.austrian.com/)) sends to your browser when you visit a website.   
Depending on the settings of your browser, a cookie file is saved or rejected. If the file is saved, our web server will be able to recognize your computer. During later visits and when switching between functions that require a password, a cookie will spare you the trouble of repeating various entries. Cookies therefore facilitate an easier use of websites that require entering user data. 

In general, cookies do not pose a threat to your computer, as they are only text modules that cannot be run as a stand-alone programme. 

We use cookies in order to find out about our website visitors’ preferences and thus design our pages in the most optimal way. When you visit our website we store your IP address, the pages you visit on our site as well as the date and the duration of your visit. Our cookies will be deleted thirty days after your visit at the latest. You may also refuse to accept cookies on your computer. 

Activating the relevant settings on your browser allows you to disable cookies. In that case, please note that you may not be able to use all functions of our website in full. By using our website you agree to the further use of the collected data by Google & Adobe. 

**Tracking of our website  
**  
We make use of the Adobe Online Marketing Suite powered by Omniture to store web data and information („data“) as a host. Omniture is an „ASP“ (Application Service Provider), which provides a service called SiteCatalyst for tracking and analyzing customer websites. All data collected by Adobe through our web pages remain the customer’s property and will be treated by Adobe as proprietary and confidential information. As such, Adobe will not disclose any information to third parties. Adobe will not verify, release, forward, print or refer to such data unless specifically requested by the customer or legally required. Individual sets of data may sometimes be viewed or used in the context of problem-solving, support, invoicing or if legally required. The customers remain responsible for safeguarding the confidentiality and safety of their usernames and passwords needed for logging-in to their accounts. 

**Right to information  
**  
Upon request we will inform you whether or not your personal data have been stored with us, respectively what kind of data those are. Should the information stored be false despite our efforts to maintain accuracy and currentness of data, we will correct the data upon your request. 

You have the right to information on and the correction or deletion of stored personal data under the provisions of the Austrian Data Protection Act (in particular §§ 26 – 28 DSG 2000) at any time.
